[{"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339339", "question": "What actress played the role of Pamela Barnes Ewing on the TV show \"Dallas\"?", "answer": "Victoria Principal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe65dc71f3c0ead6880d621", "question": "What did God place at the east of the Garden of Eden after he drove out Adam and Eve?", "answer": "Cherubims", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae27", "question": "Which famous explorer was killed in the Hawaiian Islands in 1779?", "answer": "James Cook", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b73b", "question": "Retsina is a wine traditionally made in which country?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa44", "question": "What is the capital of Philippines?", "answer": "Manila", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffa5623c73aa70ea0b70b28", "question": "In which state of the United States would you find Fort Knox?", "answer": "Kentucky", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58d1158c4fea7fe947a22267", "question": "Banjul is the capital of which country?", "answer": "The Gambia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59e80272de59ea584496fe96", "question": "What river is Liverpool situated on?", "answer": "Mersey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5c3e9b27ebfabb9c85d8a982", "question": "Which Hollywood celebrity was born Dino Crocetti in 1917?", "answer": "Dean Martin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea7990ff048f679a45abe3", "question": "What is a scientist who specializes in soil and crops called?", "answer": "Agronomist", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af21", "question": "What organisation was founded in 1961 by British lawyer Peter Benenson?", "answer": "Amnesty International", "category": "history"}, {"id": "596dfd6b9616e6c6d4eba4f5", "question": "What country was the first to send an object to the Moon?", "answer": "The Soviet Union", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399f4", "question": "What was the name of Archie\u2019s wife on the TV show \"All in the Family\"?", "answer": "Edith", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acb0", "question": "Who was the director of the FBI from 1924 to 1972?", "answer": "J. Edgar Hoover", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a748", "question": "What island in California was once called Pelican Island?", "answer": "Alcatraz Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefc3906ce05a3942286f24", "question": "Lindsey Buckingham is the lead guitarist for what British-American band?", "answer": "Fleetwood Mac", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd11", "question": "What was the original brand of cereal whose mascot was Wendell?", "answer": "Cinnamon Toast Crunch", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a1c", "question": "What famous fictional cannibal made his first appearance in the 1981 novel \"Red Dragon\"?", "answer": "Hannibal Lecter", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd2d09a2596a59cbdfbd37e", "question": "Who said, \"I don't like that man. I must get to know him better\"?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ab0ec8baab681b09292169", "question": "What is the name of the theme song of the TV show 'CSI: Cyber'?", "answer": "I Can See for Miles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5f16516af9b80650dbe7f93c", "question": "Which Mormon founded Salt Lake City?", "answer": "Brigham Young", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5febd6997e83c707845b216a", "question": "What was Forrest Gump's favorite pastime?", "answer": "Running", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab949d86faa38a764be50e", "question": "What company made the LFA?", "answer": "Lexus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58d076cb870e6f05ba60085e", "question": "In Shakespeare's \"The Taming of the Shrew\", who is the shrew's more desireable sister?", "answer": "Bianca", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aa1", "question": "What legendary jazz trumpeter was nicknamed \"Satchmo\"?", "answer": "Louie Armstrong", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab15dabaab681b0929217e", "question": "What was the world\u2019s first mass-produced car to feature an all-aluminium body?", "answer": "Honda NSX", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff256e031a458464a93c462", "question": "What garnish makes the Gibson cocktail different from a martini?", "answer": "Pearl onion", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339502", "question": "What movie includes the quote, \"That rug really tied the room together\"?", "answer": "The Big Lebowski", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6008da63f4f3bc4a292f8615", "question": "What did John Wilkes Booth shout after he shot President Lincoln?", "answer": "\"Sic Semper Tyrannis\", which is Latin for \"Thus always to tyrants\".", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388bb", "question": "In Shakespeare's \"Romeo and Juliet\", what is Juliet's surname?", "answer": "Capulet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd85", "question": "What type of animal is the Japanese monster, Kamacuras?", "answer": "Praying mantis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ff7", "question": "In the Anglo-Saxon poem, who killed Grendel?", "answer": "Beowolf", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c062", "question": "Which Major League hitter drove in the most runs in a single season between 1980-89?", "answer": "Don Mattingly", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ace7", "question": "What country saw the 1979-80 hostage crisis that ended as Ronald Reagan took his oath of office?", "answer": "Iran", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bad", "question": "How many nights are there in \"Arabian Nights\"?", "answer": "1001", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe65bef1f3c0ead6880d60a", "question": "The \"Baker Rifle\" was developed and used during which military action?", "answer": "The Napoleonic Wars", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ef0", "question": "Which literary work's title character is named Willy Loman?", "answer": "Death of a Salesman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af5f", "question": "In addition to his more historic crime, Lee Harvey Oswald was charged with killing what policeman?", "answer": "J. D. Tippit", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd660f8a5bfecdd737e0839", "question": "Where did the tradition of pumpkin carving originate?", "answer": "Ireland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd6a4a76c0f9723ab15cb55", "question": "As of 2020, who is the only president buried in Washington, D.C.?", "answer": "Woodrow Wilson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b618", "question": "What would you find in a bento box?", "answer": "Food", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a816", "question": "The two largest islands in the Mediterranean Sea are part of what country?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "597cd9dae347d002c297e4d0", "question": "What became the tallest building in London after its official opening in October 1965?", "answer": "Post Office Tower", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fec8d25ec223966ae8f884f", "question": "Who said this in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"? \"Hope is a dangerous thing. Hope can drive a man insane.\"", "answer": "Red", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff66f6b52a821ff76ae8b1f", "question": "In Tennessee, it\u2019s illegal to hold office if you\u2019ve done what?", "answer": "Fought in a duel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5be581475415ba52ed6f0abf", "question": "What is the first name of the protagonist in H. G. Wells' \"The History of Mr Polly\"?", "answer": "Alfred", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59523f3b736d4be723796b57", "question": "Which event was Canada\u2019s anthem, \"O Canada\", originally commissioned for?", "answer": "The 1880 St. Jean-Baptiste Day ceremony", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a91d", "question": "In what US state would you find Fort Sill?", "answer": "Oklahoma", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e3", "question": "Who is the author of the \"Bourne Trilogy\" novel series?", "answer": "Robert Ludlum", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59a1a29812f2a7826b9b871e", "question": "What was the name of the first synthetic plastic ever developed?", "answer": "Bakelite", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5d0", "question": "Petroglyphs are more commonly known as what?", "answer": "Rock engravings", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1c6", "question": "What word describes the dominance of one state over a group of other states?", "answer": "Hegemony", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b11", "question": "Which of the Seven Dwarfs wears glasses?", "answer": "Doc", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59f9bb49364247bf200fb8a2", "question": "What is Eddie's last name in the TV show \"The Courtship of Eddie's Father\"?", "answer": "Corbett", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59049862cf93664eb1048686", "question": "Which band would you associate with Steve Cradock?", "answer": "Ocean Colour Scene", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5af24be2844f4236002b95b1", "question": "How many countries does Afghanistan border?", "answer": "6", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c628", "question": "What is the name of the second largest planet in our Solar System?", "answer": "Saturn", "category": "science"}, {"id": "597cdc83e347d002c297e4e8", "question": "In 1973 Roland Ohisson was buried in a coffin made of what?", "answer": "Chocolate", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac3a", "question": "What was World War I known as before World War II?", "answer": "The Great War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e4e", "question": "Whose tombstone bears the inscription \"Here Lies One Whose Name Was Writ in Water\"?", "answer": "John Keats", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601b4c1a49076251badbeacd", "question": "Which First Lady was the first born outside of America?", "answer": "Louisa Adams, the wife of John Quincy Adams, was born in London.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c319", "question": "What year was the World Wide Web launched in?", "answer": "1991", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60121cdd63c99d48cd169b19", "question": "What do the iron bars of the \"Nelson Mandela\" sculpture represent?", "answer": "Imprisonment -- Created by Marco Cianfanelli, it is located at the same spot of his arrest on R102 highway in South Africa.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ade8", "question": "In which decade was the word \"Internet\" coined?", "answer": "1980s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abb2", "question": "What US state has a Thames River?", "answer": "Connecticut", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa9a", "question": "How many stars does the New Zealand national flag have?", "answer": "Four", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fecdb35ec223966ae8f88f1", "question": "In \"Raiders of the Lost Ark,\" what chases Indy out of the Temple of the Chachapoyan Warriors?", "answer": "A giant rolling boulder", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6fb", "question": "What Olympic event is abbreviated to WAG?", "answer": "Women's Artistic Gymnastics", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcb3", "question": "What kind of fruit juice is used to mix a Bronx Cocktail?", "answer": "Orange", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58dba5c5874c93a3298b2153", "question": "\"An Inconvenient Truth\" is a 2006 documentary film directed by Davis Guggenheim about what subject?", "answer": "Global Warming", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe52c131bf59ab7d2e38106", "question": "Bubble wrap was originally designed to be what?", "answer": "Wallpaper", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397fb", "question": "Who had a 1982 No.1 hit with \"Happy Talk\"?", "answer": "Captain Sensible", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0d6", "question": "Who was called \"The Hero of San Juan Hill\"?", "answer": "Theodore Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339213", "question": "What is the make of the car used as a time machine in the movie \"Back to the Future\"?", "answer": "DeLorean", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c54d", "question": "Kimberlite contains what precious stone?", "answer": "Diamond", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5e90fe44d7247dfc0fa00308", "question": "Who was the first character Walt Disney created?", "answer": "Oswald the Lucky Rabbit", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac0f", "question": "Moroni is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "Comoros", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a728c666bcd28c119383286", "question": "What year was the first edition of \"The Guinness Book of Records\" published?", "answer": "1955", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5909cc26bb53d1af658864de", "question": "Which singer sang \"I Believe in Father Christmas\"?", "answer": "Greg Lake", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e5d", "question": "Who provided the original voice for Daffy Duck?", "answer": "Mel Blanc", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390e9", "question": "How old was writer Arthur C. Clarke when he passed away in 2008?", "answer": "90", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b45a", "question": "Who led over 900 followers in a mass suicide in 1978?", "answer": "Jim Jones", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c214", "question": "Which country were the 1932 Winter Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "United States", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a08", "question": "What snack shares its name with the famous cartoon strip by Charles M. Schulz?", "answer": "Peanuts", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb2c", "question": "In what country is Absolut vodka made?", "answer": "Sweden", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d70", "question": "What classic novel's subtitle is \"A Space Odyssey\"?", "answer": "2001", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b98", "question": "Whose paintings include \"Campbell's Soup Can\" and \"Green Coca-Cola Bottles\"?", "answer": "Andy Warhol", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd00", "question": "What South African antelope lent its name to a brand of athletic shoe?", "answer": "The rhebok", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fe1", "question": "At what New York hotel was Sid Vicious accused of killing Nancy Spungen?", "answer": "The Chelsea Hotel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af3e", "question": "What was Franklin D. Roosevelt's middle name?", "answer": "Delano", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5e5", "question": "Barn, Burrowing, and Great Horned are species of what bird?", "answer": "Owl", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a9e93567ccba3ffe45786c5", "question": "What word is used to describe \"bell shaped flowers\"?", "answer": "Campanulate", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399a5", "question": "What Hanna-Barbera cartoon characters were patterned after Ed Norton from the TV series \"The Honeymooners\"?", "answer": "Yogi Bear and Barney Rubble", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff6668652a821ff76ae8af8", "question": "What is the name of the wood Noah used in building his ark?", "answer": "Gopher wood", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dd0", "question": "What comedian has real-life twin sons named Matthew and Gregory?", "answer": "Ray Romano", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339402", "question": "Which actor played the role of the Grinch in the 2000 movie \"How the Grinch Stole Christmas\"?", "answer": "Jim Carrey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c869", "question": "What tree's edible seeds were once used to weigh diamonds?", "answer": "The carob tree's", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133922e", "question": "Who stars in the semi-autobiographical movie \"Purple Rain\"?", "answer": "Prince", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c3e9a56ebfabb9c85d8a97a", "question": "What name is given to the broad gap between the Saturn's A ring and B ring?", "answer": "The Cassini Division", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe4de1406d333868d34d70e", "question": "Mustafa Kemal was the first President of which country?", "answer": "Turkey", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bae7", "question": "In what year did both \"Mad Magazine\" and \"The National Enquirer\" debut?", "answer": "1952", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dd3", "question": "At age 17, who played the title schoolgirl in \"The Bachelor and the Bobby-Soxer\"?", "answer": "Shirley Temple", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abf2", "question": "In what sort of landscape would you find an erg?", "answer": "Desert", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd56", "question": "The Peabody Award is an award given in what field?", "answer": "Radio and television", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338db2", "question": "According to the full title of Richard Wagner's \"Ring Cycle\", the fabulous ring belongs to what race of dwarves?", "answer": "The Nibelung", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f5c", "question": "Who painted the world famous \"Mona Lisa\"?", "answer": "Leonardo da Vinci", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59523d4a736d4be723796b40", "question": "Which Toronto street was once thought to be the world\u2019s longest street?", "answer": "Yonge", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aab", "question": "Who said, \"Do give books - religious or otherwise - for Christmas\"?", "answer": "Lenore Hershey", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59008cf8cf842fa4c4ba96a5", "question": "What is the capital of Poland?", "answer": "Warsaw", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58be2dac8faf425cf37add81", "question": "What is the capital of the Isle of Man?", "answer": "Douglas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5bbd4d3c00d154d7af00b8d4", "question": "In the music video \"Opposites Attract\", what is the name of the cat Paula Abdul dances with?", "answer": "MC Skat Kat", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdc121c469bb8041d07a07a", "question": "What popular diet cola soft drink first appeared in 1963?", "answer": "Tab", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae5e", "question": "Who did Prince Charles wed in a \"wedding fit for a prince\" in 2005?", "answer": "Camilla Parker Bowles", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c662", "question": "What is the longest and heaviest bone in the human body?", "answer": "Femur", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8e9", "question": "On a standard computer keyboard, what letter is to the right of the letter K?", "answer": "L", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b26e", "question": "Architect Walter Gropius founded what famous German art school in Weimar in 1919?", "answer": "The Bauhaus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff0b65ae662d71a53651006", "question": "Who played Anita in the first Broadway production of West Side Story?", "answer": "Chita Rivera", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac2c", "question": "What line divided the North and South in the U.S. Civil War?", "answer": "The Mason-Dixon line", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f46", "question": "Who created the character of Br'er Bear?", "answer": "Joel Chandler Harris", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a57d", "question": "Kodiak Island is the largest island in which US state?", "answer": "Alaska", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "592eae4ff83302ff91e46487", "question": "In which 1940s Disney film would you find a rabbit named Thumper?", "answer": "Bambi", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aab", "question": "Teri Garr and Jessica Lange were both nominated for Best Supporting Actress Oscars for what 1982 movie?", "answer": "Tootsie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adc0", "question": "In which country did the My Lai massacre take place?", "answer": "Vietnam", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398fd", "question": "On July 10, 1975, Cher filed for divorce from what musician?", "answer": "Gregg Allman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff7c2e22b316f4693fb67a4", "question": "Mikey, Lee and Will are the Co-Founders of which famous West London based global streetwear brand?", "answer": "Trapstar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f5a", "question": "What New York cardiologist published his bestselling \"Diet Revolution\" in 1972?", "answer": "Robert Atkins", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601b48b749076251badbeaa5", "question": "Who was the oldest person to travel in space?", "answer": "John Glenn -- He was 77-years-old when he returned to space on the Space Shuttle Discovery's STS-95 mission.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a52f", "question": "Which US state is home to Newberry National Volcanic Monument?", "answer": "Oregon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5ff", "question": "What was Cape Kennedy renamed to in 1973?", "answer": "Cape Canaveral", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff7c2c42b316f4693fb67a3", "question": "American supermarket chain Whole Foods is owned by which mega company?", "answer": "Amazon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b16", "question": "What actor did Melanie Griffith marry, and divorce, twice?", "answer": "Don Johnson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd66d47a5bfecdd737e089e", "question": "What is the most valuable stock exchange in the world?", "answer": "New York Stock Exchange", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adf3", "question": "In what city did the Hindenburg airship disaster occur?", "answer": "Lakehurst, New Jersey", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b746", "question": "The serial killer Larry Eyler was also known as what?", "answer": "The Highway Killer/The Interstate Killer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abbd", "question": "Where might you drink Retsina wine?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601219f963c99d48cd169afe", "question": "What is the tallest dog breed in the world?", "answer": "Irish Wolfhound -- A Great Dane named Zeus holds the record as tallest dog ever.  As a breed, the Irish Wolfhound is the tallest.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdab3a30b8cce1e6fda7046", "question": "What is \"jaggery\", regularly used in Indian cooking?", "answer": "Sugar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe735dfeec85e375820b254", "question": "What did John Wilkes Booth shout after he shot President Lincoln?", "answer": "Sic Semper Tyrannis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339774", "question": "Which company created the Oscar-winning film Finding Nemo?", "answer": "Pixar Animation Studios", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339804", "question": "What movie soundtrack is Eric Clapton's \"Tears in Heaven\" from?", "answer": "Rush", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a415", "question": "What US city is home to the annual \"All-American Soap Box Derby\"?", "answer": "Akron, Ohio", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e6c", "question": "Who played the blind character in the movie \"Daredevil\"?", "answer": "Ben Affleck", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b31e", "question": "Constance Markievicz, became the first ever what In 1918?", "answer": "British female MP", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339827", "question": "Who was the chief photographer for \"Rolling Stone\" magazine from 1970 to 1983?", "answer": "Annie Leibowitz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58c9f7b1b4e2c7fbd389674b", "question": "How is a Long black coffee different from an Americano?", "answer": "The espresso is poured on top of the hot water, instead of before", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be53", "question": "Who built the world's first free-standing geodesic dome in 1949?", "answer": "Buckminster Fuller", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be22", "question": "In what country was actor Rick Fox born?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe9053601dd7bf43be5e87a", "question": "What does \"In vino veritas\" translate into?", "answer": "In wine is truth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "594a64142ebb971c1417fba0", "question": "The song \"I Talk to the Trees\" comes from what musical?", "answer": "Paint Your Wagon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339853", "question": "In \"Spirited Away\", Yubabas giant baby Boh gets turned into what?", "answer": "Mouse", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f34", "question": "Which band member of The Germs died of drug overdose?", "answer": "Darby Crash", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133906c", "question": "Which famous piece of artwork depicts the \"Battle of Hastings\"?", "answer": "Bayeux Tapestry", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58d474caf8e329de4f8778a0", "question": "The Balfour Declaration was published in what year?", "answer": "1917", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b604", "question": "What war do the girls in \"Little Women\" grow up during?", "answer": "The Civil War", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abee", "question": "What is the capital of Ukraine?", "answer": "Kiev", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ab99d1f21a8909e5c332d3e", "question": "What was Harold Lloyd Jenkins' stage name?", "answer": "Conway Twitty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c85b", "question": "The \"K\" in vitamin K stands for the Danish spelling of what eleven-letter word?", "answer": "Coagulation", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff2588c31a458464a93c467", "question": "What does the Slavic word \"vodka\" translate to in English?", "answer": "\"Little water\"", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f3", "question": "What is Tchaikovsky's ballet \"Le Lac des Cygnes\" commonly called?", "answer": "Swan Lake", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e44", "question": "What two-word phrase is the first writing to appear in \"Charlotte's Web\"?", "answer": "Some pig", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cb0a", "question": "Are pumpkins fruits or vegetables?", "answer": "Fruits", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b07f", "question": "How many electoral votes did Gerald Ford get in the \u201976 election?", "answer": "240", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afa5", "question": "Which oil rig exploded in 1988 killing 167 people?", "answer": "Piper Alpha", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ab148dbaab681b09292175", "question": "The Benz Patent-Motorwagen, widely regarded as the world\u2019s first automobile, was first built in what year?", "answer": "1885", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefa5526ce05a3942286ebd", "question": "Which meal made the flight crew and some of the passengers ill in the comedy \"Airplane!\"?", "answer": "Fish", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd41", "question": "What color is New York's Staten Island Ferry?", "answer": "Orange", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c54b", "question": "What is the common name for iron oxide, which appears after iron has been exposed to air and water?", "answer": "Rust", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395fa", "question": "What were the names of rival gangs in \"West Side Story\"?", "answer": "The Jets and The Sharks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad7e759b24f84e0b9f9ffb8", "question": "Which Star Wars villain shares a voice with the narrator of the 1995 film \"Judge Dredd\"?", "answer": "Darth Vader", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b59a", "question": "Which major car company owns the luxury automotive brand Lexus?", "answer": "Toyota", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133930b", "question": "In Disney's movie \"The Lion King\", what does \"Hakuna Matata\" mean?", "answer": "No worries", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b245", "question": "In 2002, Sony ended production of its recorders using what doomed video standard?", "answer": "Betamax", "category": "history"}, {"id": "594a633f2ebb971c1417fb98", "question": "Which Queen of England, and wife of Henry VIII, had six fingers on one of her hands?", "answer": "Anne Boleyn", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe64163ae7e414034b5aeac", "question": "What was the name of Al Capone's criminal organization?", "answer": "The Outfit", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a952", "question": "What is the only US state that ends with the state's own postal abbreviation?", "answer": "Kentucky", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefbff36ce05a3942286f07", "question": "Which two popular actors starred in the lead roles in the film \"Rounders\"?", "answer": "Matt Damon and Edward Norton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c574", "question": "Which element has the chemical symbol \"No\"?", "answer": "Nobelium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "595241af736d4be723796b63", "question": "What color is human blood that isn't oxygenated?", "answer": "Red", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0a6", "question": "What was the name of the restaurant the TV series \"Happy Days\"?", "answer": "Arnolds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398ca", "question": "What comedian is remembered for his saying \"Everybody wants ta get inta de act\"?", "answer": "Jimmy Durante", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c11b", "question": "The Stasi were an intelligence organisation in what country?", "answer": "German Democratic Republic", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea7a8dff048f679a45abec", "question": "What does the human lacrimal gland produce?", "answer": "Tears", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59a1a20512f2a7826b9b8717", "question": "What 1980's cartoon was a showcase for \"New Wave\" Music videos?", "answer": "Kidd Video", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b45", "question": "What actor played Lex Luthor in the 1978 film \"Superman\"?", "answer": "Gene Hackman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5989ae11cb8751d53e7d7613", "question": "What is the name of the pub in the 1945 film \"Pink String and Sealing Wax\"?", "answer": "The Dolphin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd2d6e92596a59cbdfbd3af", "question": "What was Henry Ford\u2019s original design for a car called?", "answer": "Quadricycle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c300", "question": "Which elephant can't be domesticated, the African or Indian?", "answer": "The African", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60173f7444491cbd7c5a17b1", "question": "Who was the first American woman to get her pilot's license?", "answer": "Harriet Quimby got her pilot's license in 1911 after persuading the magazine she worked for to pay for her flying lessons.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59a553423e1c6f9840ba31a2", "question": "In ancient Rome what was the \"Tabularium\"?", "answer": "\"Hall of Public Records\", or the official records office", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afd1", "question": "Who became the 17th president, after Abraham Lincoln was assassinated?", "answer": "Andrew Johnson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3e4", "question": "What type of wool can come from a rabbit?", "answer": "Angora", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd6a7486c0f9723ab15cb5d", "question": "What was the first toy advertised on television?", "answer": "Mr. Potato Head", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a9", "question": "Who voices the character of scientist and inventor Professor John I.Q. Nerdelbaum Frink Jr. on \"The Simpsons\"?", "answer": "Hank Azaria", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133959d", "question": "What is Indiana Jones searching for in the movie \"Indiana Jones and The Last Crusade\"?", "answer": "The Holy Grail", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a34", "question": "What movie western earned Gene Hackman his second acting Oscar?", "answer": "Unforgiven", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af05", "question": "What was Abraham Lincoln's wife's name?", "answer": "Mary Todd Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe73801eec85e375820b25f", "question": "What islands are located in the Bering Strait between Russia and Alaska?", "answer": "Diomede Islands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389fd", "question": "Who's Kanga's son in the \"Winnie-the-Pooh\" stories?", "answer": "Roo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c21", "question": "Sting was the lead singer of which popular band?", "answer": "The Police", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a5b", "question": "In 1994, Mary Ramsey replaced Natalie Merchant as the lead singer for what group?", "answer": "10,000 Maniacs", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d68", "question": "In the Bible, who is the mother of the prophet Samuel?", "answer": "Hannah", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b11", "question": "What rapper married and divorced a woman named Kim Scott twice?", "answer": "Eminem", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5921fc96a4edfd43a087adc0", "question": "Sweet Baby Broccoli is another name for what vegetable?", "answer": "Broccolini", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe9f0ecff048f679a45aaab", "question": "Verminophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Germs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ac0", "question": "Allan \"Rocky\" Lane provided the voice of what 1960's sitcom title character?", "answer": "Mister Ed", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a382", "question": "What is the capital of the Netherlands?", "answer": "Amsterdam", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff7bd562b316f4693fb678d", "question": "In the 1980s, how did American Airlines famously save $40,000?", "answer": "By removing a single olive from each salad served on American Airlines flights", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f74dfa9e54d890926f701", "question": "According to Russian law, a homeless person must be where after 10 pm?", "answer": "At home", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca7c", "question": "What is the significance of the moth found in the Harvard Mark I computer?", "answer": "First computer \"bug\"", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf80", "question": "What is a tightrope walker called?", "answer": "Funambulist", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aef8", "question": "During the early 1900s, over 12 million immigrants landed on what New York island?", "answer": "Ellis Island", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339847", "question": "Who released the album \"I Got Dem Ol' Kozmic Blues Again Mama\"?", "answer": "Janis Joplin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8e2", "question": "Which Washington, D.C. street is often used as shorthand for the lobbying industry?", "answer": "K", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b787", "question": "What food is usually left out for Santa Claus on Christmas Eve?", "answer": "Milk and cookies", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c688", "question": "Who took a leave of absence in the mid 1940's from his position at Cal Tech to direct the Manhattan Project?", "answer": "Robert Oppenheimer", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b01", "question": "What is the name of the crab who looks after Ariel in Disney's \"The Little Mermaid\"?", "answer": "Sebastian", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338df4", "question": "In 1853, what author founded a successful daily journal called \"Le Mousquetaire\"?", "answer": "Alexandre Dumas", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392a9", "question": "Which Hollywood star is married to Matthew Broderick?", "answer": "Sarah Jessica Parker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe734a7eec85e375820b23a", "question": "How did General Erwin Rommel die?", "answer": "Suicide", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9ed", "question": "How many vehicles did the original \"Gran Turismo\" video game have?", "answer": "140", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339248", "question": "What animated movie takes its name from a Yiddish word meaning monster?", "answer": "Shrek", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b8d4a72b42d4a3561a9efb", "question": "In the comic book series \"Strangers in Paradise\", what nickname did Katchoo go by when working in L.A. as an escort?", "answer": "Baby June", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a630", "question": "What river defines the southern border of Oklahoma?", "answer": "Red River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015e63afe83fe1f2a824bc9", "question": "Who ultimately succeeded King Alfred the Great as \"King of the Anglo-Saxons\"?", "answer": "Edward the Elder", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cfc", "question": "In which movie did Ione Skye portray a witch?", "answer": "Four Rooms", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339224", "question": "Who celebrated is 111th birthday during \"The Lord of the Rings: The Fellowship of the Ring?\"", "answer": "Bilbo Baggins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5921fdf9a4edfd43a087adcb", "question": "Disney's 2013 film \"Frozen\" was inspired by which fairy tale?", "answer": "The Snow Queen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397ba", "question": "What U.S. state did the Coneheads settle in after crash landing on earth?", "answer": "New Jersey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391e0", "question": "Who played Mr. Brown in the movie \"Reservoir Dogs\"?", "answer": "Quentin Tarantino", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "594a61902ebb971c1417fb88", "question": "How many hurdles are there in a 400 metres hurdle race?", "answer": "Ten", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c212", "question": "Which country were the 1928 Winter Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff6679c52a821ff76ae8afe", "question": "Which historical member of British royalty made Christmas trees mainstream there?", "answer": "Prince Albert, the German husband of Queen Victoria", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2d9", "question": "What military legend was nicknamed \"Gentleman Johnny\"?", "answer": "John Burgoyne", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b538", "question": "How many players are there on a soccer team?", "answer": "Eleven", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5a3", "question": "Which two US states do not share a border with any other state?", "answer": "Alaska and Hawaii", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9fa", "question": "What does ZIP as in ZIP code stand for?", "answer": "Zone Improvement Project", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ad9e02ee748bb36357acdec", "question": "The cities of Xai-Xai, Panda, and Beira are in what country?", "answer": "Mozambique", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf75", "question": "What does a Geophage do?", "answer": "Eats earthy substances", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb2b", "question": "What word refers to minimum attendance necessary for US Congress to conduct business?", "answer": "Quorum", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c908", "question": "What are the Chiuhauhan, Nubian, and Alaskan?", "answer": "Deserts", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c64", "question": "What Stephen King novel features an evil clown named Pennywise?", "answer": "It", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3df", "question": "Which is the only Portuguese-speaking Latin American country?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c98", "question": "What TV show takes place in the fictional city of Stuckeyville, Ohio?", "answer": "Ed", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0e4", "question": "Which pasta is shaped like a short tube?", "answer": "Ditalini", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5904a538cf93664eb10486c9", "question": "Including spin-offs and tie-ins, how many issues were released as part of the original \"Strangers in Paradise\" comic series before its planned end in 2007?", "answer": "106", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b432", "question": "What year did the Mau Mau Uprising start?", "answer": "1952", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e8d", "question": "In 1972, who became the first TV title character to get an abortion?", "answer": "Maude Findlay", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d5d", "question": "What classic movie, in which Charlton Heston is miscast as a Mexican cop, is sometimes called the last \"film noir\"?", "answer": "Touch of Evil", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133beaa", "question": "What cousin of the glockenspiel was named for its ethereal, \"heavenly\" sound?", "answer": "The celesta", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b37e", "question": "The Mason-Dixon line ran between Maryland and which other American State?", "answer": "Pennsylvania", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f96", "question": "Handel's \"Largo\" comes from which opera?", "answer": "Xerxes", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ba2", "question": "What city is the setting for the TV series \"Mad Men\"?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b7ffaf53a3a814d89068c60", "question": "What bit length did Intel's first microprocessor have?", "answer": "4", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5be57d5e5415ba52ed6f0aa6", "question": "How many minutes are in a day?", "answer": "1,440", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdad", "question": "What food item shares its name with Brad and Janet's hospitable host in \"The Rocky Horror Picture Show\"?", "answer": "A frankfurter", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c204", "question": "What year did the US host their first Olympic Games?", "answer": "1904", "category": "general"}]